

I'm a full stack software engineer with a specialization in server and client JavaScript as well as the .NET framework. With over 6 years of professional experience, I have had the opportunity to work on projects that run the gambit from federal government projects and tools, to private business enterprise web applications, to building websites for digital marketing agencies, as well as working entrepreneurially as a freelance consultant. I have had to become adaptable to work on teams both small and large and have owned significant portions of code and team processes that have had direct impact on both the organizations' growth as well as internal team

EXPERIENCE

Architect of the Capitol Full Stack Software Engineer

Sept 2020 - May 2020 • Washington, DC (remote)

- I came into an existing monolithic app migration (used once every 2yrs) from .NET 4.x to .NET Core 3.x and had to adapt to a new team unfamiliar with the app asking questions. I was the one with all the historical knowledge and context and provided insight to the team on data relationships, why decisions were made around code architecture, and clarify expected application use cases.
- I helped speed up future schema migrations by writing many different SQL scripts to be used for every 2yr cycle.
- Had a direct impact on the onboarding process for new hires and developers across the broader organization new to the codebase, by authoring all documentation for the new front end architecture and defined best practices and principles to follow.
- I impacted the efficiency of stakeholder feature demos and QA testing by creating SQL scripts to mimic specific
 application states, which were used by develoers and QA team for testing bugs and setting up feature demos,
 resulting in a more seamless workflow.
- I optimized and improved the code quality by owning the rewriting of the client application from an MVC view approach to a SPA and upgraded to React 16.5, rewriting all class-based components to functional components with hooks, implemented the Context API for global storage and authored over 330 individual tests across 110 test suites to react 80% code coverage. Since I wrote the client app 2 years prior, it gave me the opportunity to catch all my oversights and apply newfound knowledge.
- Tech Used: .NET, C#, SQL, React, Jest, SignalR, Hangfire, React Testing Library, Sass, Bootstrap, ESLint, Prettier, Team Foundation Server

Gloo, LLC Senior Software Engineer - Web

June 2019 - Sept 2020 • Boulder, CO

- Worked on Accounts/Registration team for onboarding new users and organizations registering with the Gloo
 platform. We solved the problem for tracking where a new user's source was, and in turn their proper destination to be, scaling for an SSO model across the platform's host of products. Our UIs had a direct impact on every
 user, optimizing the conversion rates for successful registrations through efficient user flows, registrations,
 password resets, verification codes via email, etc.
- As the only FTE web engineer on our team, I was responsible for ensuring our Gloo Web team policies and practices were being upheld through code reviews, guidance, and patience.
- Contributed to the internal Gloo Web team by authoring two NPM packages to implement custom Google Analytics and Facebook tags within our Next.js applications.
- I sped up our onboarding process for web contributors by spearheading a Naming Conventions Best Practices
 doc on front end code for React, Apollo GraphQL, Rosie, Jest, Next.js, etc. authoring it, coordinating with team
 mtembers for input, and getting everyone to sign off on it, which we later adopted and included our onboarding
 docs for new hires or contractors.
- Tech Used: Microservices, Next.js, Apollo GraphQL, Express, CircleCI, Heroku, Docker, Kubernetes, Jest,
 Cypress, React Testing Library, Emotion, Material UI, Formik, Rollbar

SKILLS

Programming Languages

C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, GraphQL, HTML, CSS

Frameworks & Tooling

Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Apollo React, Vue, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Redux, React Native Jest, React Testing Library, Enzyme, Cypress Git, CircleCI, Heroku, Webpack, TFS, Jira

Other

Communication, project planning, team collaboration

Certifications

Certified ScrumMaster ScrumAlliance Certificant ID #355624

EDUCATION

SeedPaths

Aug 2014 - Oct 2014 • Denver, CO 8-week intensive software development boot camp learning full stack, object-oriented programming in

Louisiana State University

Aug 2008 - May 2011 • Baton Rouge, LA Landscape Architecture & Communication Studies

ENTREPRENUEAL

Althea Web Services, LLC

June 2016 – Present • Denver, CO
Sole-proprietor of a business where I provide web
development services via freelancing or contractual
agreements. I also operate under this name as a
means to publish personal projects and secure my
own intellectual property.

Architect of the Capitol Full Stack Software Engineer

Mar 2018 - June 2019 • Washington, DC (remote)

Project - Compass

- Lead the front end development during a redesign of the internal SharePoint intranet for employees for organizational news, events, and other important information
- Planned and created an internal tool for creating custom SharePoint content, catered to the site, that employees could use to help simplify and speed up the process, resulting in less stress and overall efficiency
- Helped mentor other team members on pieces of code / development concepts when the time was needed

Project - Senate Suites

- Owned the client application development during an enterprise app redesign in .NET, migrating from an MVC architecture with views written in Razor, to views written in React, leveraging Redux and webpack for modular bundle sizes.
- Implemented test suites in Jest and Enzyme, resulting in a test coverage of 73% of all client code.
- I also supported migrating features from ColdFusion into .NET, and implemented WebAPIs for a RESTful approach, resulting in a faster and less buggy app.
- · Worked directly with stakeholders of the project, organizing and planning feature work, tech debt, and long term trajectory.
- Tech Used: C#, .NET, SQL, React, TypeScript, Redux, Jest, Enzyme, jQuery, SharePoint, CAML, Webpack, ESLint, Less

Evolver, Inc. Front End Software Engineer

Apr 2017 - Mar 2018 • Centennial, CO

- Dramatically improved user experience and optimized client code by refactoring .NET MVC w/ ¡Query to using React/Redux in a web app with over 10,000 users.
- Improved our deployment pipeline by implementing a testing harness in Jest and Enzyme covering over 75% of client code, and configuring linting and formatting for overall code quality.
- Tech Used: C#, .NET, React, ES6 JavaScript, CSS, Sass, Webpack, Redux, Jest, Enzyme, Jira, jQuery

Crawford & O'Brien Lead Web Developer

Sep 2015 – Apr 2017 • Tempe, AZ (remote)

- Served as the lead developer for a digital marketing agency performing any and all tech related tasks for over 40 clients, including but not limited to: development of Wordpress and Shopify sites with custom themes, continued support requests, DNS and content migrations, emails, security, backups, site speed optimizations, SEO, etc.
- Working directly with the clients to find out their needs and accomplishing the tasks needed to meet those. Being the main point of contact for direct requests for their websites and interacting one-on-one with them.
- Directed and managed 3 junior developers, delegating tasks, implementing and overseeing processes of web development, and documentation for our small department.
- Tech Used: WordPress, PHP, Shopify, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Google Analytics, WooCommerce, Trello

Access-Now Web Developer/Designer

Dec 2014 - Jan 2015 • Denver, CO

- Designed and builtw dynamic, responsive websites and custom logos and marketing materials for a digital marketing agency
- Tech Used: WordPress, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, cPanel, Plesk, Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, and Illustrator